hostpresto.com 2019-07-01

# Enix Ltd / HostPresto! Privacy Policy

  * Security
  * Compliance
  * GDPR
  * FAQ
  * Privacy
  * Terms of Use
  * Abuse

## Introduction

Enix Ltd, trading as HostPresto! collects and processes your personal data, please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. 

## Information we collect from you as a client

We collect information in a variety of ways, these include the web forms you complete on the HostPresto! Website and any emails exchanged with us.

We endeavour to minimise the data we hold about you and will only keep it for up to 7 days after you cease to be a client unless there is a legal obligation to retain something for longer (e.g. invoice details). 

We store general category information such as;

  * Company names
  * Individual contact names, first and last. 
  * Email addresses 
  * Postal addresses 
  * Phone numbers 
  * VAT/Tax IDs 
  * IP Addresses 
  * Time Zone’s 
  * Browser type and operating system 
  * Any referring websites that sent you to us 

Where we are requested to do so, we also store payment information including credit card details.

## The information you share with us through our services

The flexibility of our hosting services means you can potentially host any form of data imaginable. We will never use that data for any purposes other than those highlighted in our terms of service.

As part of these terms, you are prohibited from allowing any form of illegal data to enter our systems and we, Enix Ltd (HostPresto!) will act only as a data processor for this data. The fundamental rights of the data subjects are your responsibility as the data controller, these include but are not limited to;

  * The right to be informed
  * The right of access
  * The right to rectification
  * The right to erasure
  * The right to restrict processing
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to object

## Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.

We use industry best practices to keep your data secure and maintain its confidentiality, integrity and availability. We will also be happy to review and discuss any contracts that you wish to implement with us prior to us processing this category of data.

## The legal basis for processing your personal data

We will only process your personal data when it is in yours or our legitimate interests and those interests are not overridden by your rights and freedoms or, in relation to marketing and processing credit/debit card information, where we have your consent to do so.

## How does hostpresto! Use personal data

All our data is stored within the European Economic Area, in general, we do not transfer personal data outside the EAA apart from when it is required to provision certain products and services, for example to various domain registries (ICANN and others) for whois requirements.

Most of the personal data that we hold is used in your legitimate interests in the provision, renewal and management of products and services to you, this includes the order process, invoicing, support and general enquiries. Other uses include;

### Direct Marketing

With your explicit consent, we may contact you via email about other products and services that we feel are relevant and in your legitimate interest. You may opt out of these emails at any time by contacting us or via the client’s account area on the HostPresto! Website.

### Third party Marketing

We use marketing features where third-party vendors (including Google) display our adverts on websites and use cookies based on a user’s prior visits to the HostPresto! website.

You can control how these cookies capture and process your information, more information can be found under the section “How you can control advertising cookies” on [Google’s website](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies). 

We process your data in this way to assist us in collecting statistical information on the HostPresto! website and to determine the performance of our advertisement strategies. This process may also capture data in relation to age, gender and interests.

### Payment Gateways

During the billing process, your credit/debit card details are processed with SagePay and PayPal, these are well known and legitimate payment processing gateways and have their own privacy policies that dictate how they handle your information. These can be found here;

  * <https://www.sagepay.co.uk/policies>
  * <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/legalhub-full>

Where we feel it is your best interests to do so, we do store payment card information ourselves. This information is encrypted and rest and during transport and we run regular PCI compliance scans to ensure we are following best practices with our security procedures. You can at any time, request us to remove this information by contacting us or via the client’s account area on the HostPresto! Website.

### Disclosure of your information

HostPresto! In general, does not disclose personal data to any third parties, except in cases where client’s permission has been gained or to provision products/services, e.g. to domain name registries for whois requirements.

However, if we sell or buy any businesses or assets, those entities may also gain access to your data.

We may also disclose your data if we have a legal duty to disclose or share it to comply with any legal obligation or to enforce or apply our Terms of Service or other agreements.

We may also disclose your data to protect the rights, property, or safety of Enix Ltd (HostPresto!), our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## Your right to be informed

You have the right to be informed about the collection and use of your personal data, this privacy policy informs you of our purposes for processing your personal data, our retention periods for that personal data, and who it will be shared with.

## Your right of access

You have the right to access your personal data and supplementary information and can request a copy by emailing privacy@hostpresto.com or via the contact form on the HostPresto! Website. 

## Your right to rectification

You have the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified or completed if it is incomplete and any requests of this nature should be emailed to privacy@hostpresto.com or via the contact form on the HostPresto! Website. 

## Your right to erasure

You have the right to have personal data erased, this right is not absolute and only applies in certain circumstances and any requests should be emailed to privacy@hostpresto.com or via the contact form on the HostPresto! Website and we will respond within one month. 

## Your right to restrict processing

You have the right to request the restriction or suppression of your personal data, this is not an absolute right and only applies in certain circumstances and any requests should be emailed to privacy@hostpresto.com or via the contact form on the HostPresto! Website and we will respond within one month. 

## Your right to data portability

You have the right to move, copy or transfer personal data easily from our services to another service in a safe and secure way, without hindrance to usability. Data portability requests should be emailed to privacy@hostpresto.com or via the contact form on the HostPresto! Website. 

## Your right to object

Any objection to the processing of your data will require us to stop processing the personal data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims and enforcement of our terms of service (https://hostpresto.com/terms) 

## Your rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.

We do not automatically profile any personal data 

## Your right to complain

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. We do however request that you give us an opportunity to resolve any complaints by emailing us at privacy@hostpresto.com or contacting us via the form on the HostPresto! Website.

For more information about our local data protection authority please visit the Information Commissioner’s Office’s website here; [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/).

## Our privacy information

Our Data Controller & Data Protection Officer’s details are as follows;

  * Name: Elliot Pearse
  * Address: 16-18 Barnes Wallis Road, Segensworth East, PO15 5TT
  * Email: info@enixltd.com

## Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy.
